-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译：choc 青色石头
校对&时间轴：小魉
显然 我错误估算了一些事情
Obviously, I miscalculated a few things.
艾迪 我知道你就在里面
Eddie! I know you're in there!
如果某天 生活远远脱离了正常的梦想...
Why is it that the moment your life exceeds your wildest dreams...
你输入的密码...
The access code you have entered...
而问题又如芒在刺
The knife appears at your back?
你输入的密码有误...
The access code you have entered is invalid...
好吧 听我说...
Well, I'll tell you one thing...
我绝不会让他们碰我一指头
I will never let them touch me.
我的邻居 一定已经开门抱怨了
My neighbor, who must have opened his door to complain.
下一个就是你了 艾迪 我们进来了
You're gonna be next, Eddie! We're coming in!
对一个拥有四位数智商的人 我一定错过了什么
For a guy with a four digit IQ, I must have missed something.
却并不多
And I hadn't missed much.
距离影响整个世界只有一步之遥
I'd come this close to having an impact on the world.
而现在 唯一会受到我行为影响的只有...
And now, the only thing I'd have an impact on...
...人行道
...was the sidewalk.
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
永无止境
看见那个家伙了吗
You see that guy?
就是我 不久之前的我
That was me, not so long ago.
除了瘾君子和酒鬼 还有谁能这幅德行
What kind of guy without a drug or alcohol problem looks this way?
毫无疑问只有作家 说来也怪
Only a writer. Strangely enough,
居然没人愿意相信我还有书约在身
nobody believed that I actually had a book contract.
嗯 虽然是以科幻小说的形式
Well, it's masquerading as a sci-fi novel,
但我的本意是想表现
but it's really, uh, my own personal manifesto
身处21世纪个人的困境
about the plight of the individual in the 21st century.
我创造出了一个乌托邦的社会
I sort of created a utopian society
而在那个社会里...我们...嗯...
where we all sort of... Uh... Uh...
非常的...真的...
It's really... it's really...
呃...
Uh...
今天一定要写出点什么
Today was the day I was gonna kick its ass.
来吧 来吧 加油...
Here we go. Here we go. Here we go...
一定会很棒的
It was gonna be great.
只要待在房间里 肯花上时间
Just gotta put in the time. Stay in the room.
这就是关键
That's the key concept.
不能离开房间
Don't leave the room.
就这样过去了几周
A few weeks passed this way.
也许是之后的几个月
Maybe a few months.
至少我还有琳迪
At least I still had Lindy.
就这样吗
Just like that?
行了 艾迪 这也算是意料之中的事了
Come on, Eddie, This is hardly a surprise,
完全意料之外
I'm surprised,
别这样 好吧 让我...
Let's just not do this, OK? Let me...
我周五就要交给玛勒90页的稿子
I'm gonna hand in 90 pages to Marla on Friday,
你不如等等看她的评价再...
If you just wait to see what she says...
艾迪
Eddie,
什么      我明白的
What?        I know how it's going,
我是你的...
I'm your...
我曾经是你的女朋友
I was your girlfriend,
但这个词却不能充分说明你对于我的意义
That word doesn't even begin to describe what you are to me,
伙伴? 泄欲对象?
Partner? Squeeze?
爱侣 恋人
Paramour, Inamorata,
清扫女工 还有自动提款机
Cleaning lady, Bank,
谢谢 马上给您送过来
Thanks, Be right back,
只是...
Be that a...
但我的东西也都是你的啊
What's mine is yours, too,
你很清楚 我愿意与你共度余生
and you know I want to share the rest of my life with you,
我想过也许我们应该...      别求婚 千万别
I was thinking that we should...        Don't propose,
为什么
Why not?
因为上一段婚姻就让你精疲力竭
Because it worked out so well for you last time,
这倒是真的 我结过婚 刚毕业的时候 和梅利莎
It's true, I did marry once. Right out of college, to Melissa.
我愿意
I do,
不过非常短暂
Briefly.
我做不到
This isn't working,
好吧 就算你说的都是真的 但我还是爱你啊
Well, even though everything you say is true, I still love you,
我得回去工作了
I gotta get back to work,
你还没告诉我为什么啊
You didn't even tell me what happened,
我做到了      真的吗
I got it,        You did?
嗯哼 我是个编辑了
Mm-hm, I'm an editor,
有自己的助理 你能相信吗
I'll have my own assistant, Can you believe that?
我当然相信啊 这是你应得的啊
Yeah, of course I believe it, You deserve it,
谢谢
Thanks,
好了      好吧
OK,        OK,
她是对的 那为什么还要坚持下去呢
She was right. Why stick it out?
显而易见 我已经错失良机
I had clearly missed the on-ramp.
我们都清楚真正动人心弦的是什么
We both knew what was beckoning.
在新泽西我孩提时代卧室的下铺
The lower bunk in my childhood bedroom in Jersey.
父亲满心欢喜地迎接我来到
My father happy to welcome me into the challenging field
牙科器械这一充满挑战的领域
of dental supply inventory.
艾迪・莫莱
Eddie Morra,
在所有该被弃之敝履
Of all the useless relationships better forgotten
束之高阁的无用人际关系中
and put away in mothballs,
有什么能比得上前小舅子更无用
is there any more useless than... the ex-brother-in-law?
要死了 老兄
Holy shit, man,
是有多久了 9年有没有
What has it been? Like nine years?
老天爷      嘿
God!        Hey,
你还好吗 怎么一副沦落街头的样子
You all right? You look like you're living on the streets,
过得如何
What's going on?
不算..我..嗯..我..你呢
Not much, I... Well... What am I... What's up?
嗯 写东西吧 写了不少
Uh, I'm writing, Writing a lot,
哦 你还没放弃写东西吗
Oh, you're still trying to write?
事实上 我还有书约在身
Matter of fact, I have a book contract,
真的吗      是的
Really?        Yeah,
那很好啊      你呢
That's great,        How about you?
还在贩药吗 弗恩
Are you still dealing, Vern?
我看起来还像干这行的吗      这倒是不像
Do I look like I'm still dealing?        No, you don't, No,
走吧 去喝一杯 给我说说你的书
Come on, let's go get a drink, I want to hear about this book,
不是吧 现在可是下午2点啊
I don't know, It's 2:00 in the afternoon,
这个时间你有什么问题吗
When has that ever stopped you?
怎么说      那...
So,        So...
梅利莎过得好吗
How's Melissa doing?
给      谢谢
Here you go,        Thanks,
不知道 没见过她 她搬家了 去了北部
Wouldn't know, I don't see her, She moved upstate,
好像在做什么网络房屋销售的玩意
She got some kind of Internet home sales kind of job,
带着一大堆孩子
Couple kids,
孩子 那她老公呢
Couple kids, Who's the husband?
离了 如果你问的是这个
He walked out on her, if you really want to know,
不过这和你没什么关系吧
But what do you care, man?
算起来你们两个也就结了5分钟的婚
You were married, like, five minutes,
听着 我不想谈她 不如说说你吧
Look, I don't wanna talk about her, I wanna talk about you, OK?
说说你的书 进展如何
Tell me about this book, How's it going?
嗯 书的话 呃...
Well, it's, uh...
我...我...
I'm... I'm...
我只是在逃避 用书来做借口逃避
I'm behind, I'm behind on my book,
而这个借口差不多毁了我日日夜夜的生活
And, uh, it's pretty well polluting my days and nights,
如果那是你想知道的
if you really want to know,
嗯 你已经写了多少呢      一片空白
Well, how much have you written of it?        Not one word,
灵感的问题 是吗      算是吧
Creative problems, huh?        Yeah, Mm-hm,
说不定我能帮上忙
Well, I suppose I can help you with that,
不过仅此一次
Just this once,
哦 不用 真的不用了
Oh, no, no, no, no, no,
你根本不知道这是什么      你还在贩药吗
You don't even know what it is,        You're still dealing,
老兄 我不干那玩意儿很多年了
Brother, I am light years from that now,
现在我可是某家制药企业的顾问
I've been doing, uh, some consulting for a pharmaceutical company,
什么企业 沿海那些做山寨伟哥的实验室吗
What, like some offshore lab making fake Viagra?
得了 弗恩
Come on, Vern,
不是 这可是明年就会批量生产的高档货
No, This is an exclusive product that's coming on stream next year,
已经通过了临床试验和食药局的认可
They've had clinical trials and it's FDA approved,
好吧 就算纯粹好奇心作祟吧 这...
All right, just out of curiosity and that's all...
拿出来看看吧
Let's see it,
这到底是什么
What's in it?
专家已经证实大脑里的受体
They've identified these receptors in the brain
都被触发了特殊的回路
that activate specific circuits,
知道他们都怎么说吗 我们使用的只有大脑的20%
And you how they say that we can only access 20 percent of our brain?
然而 这个东西...却能让你完全利用自己的大脑
Well, what this does... it lets you access all of it,
弗恩 看看我 算得上事业有成吗
Vern, look at me, Do I look good to you?
不过是个一无是处的倒霉蛋
I'm broke and I'm depressed off my ass,
我不觉得这么一小片反光的新型药丸
I don't think that my life's gonna take some sudden upswing
能带来翻天覆地的变化 让我名利两全
into fame and fortune by taking some shiny, brand-new designer drug,
甘特
Gant,
什么时候
When?
告诉他不行 不 你告诉他
Tell him we can't do that, No, you tell him,
不行 就是现在
No, now,
抱歉我得先走了 艾迪
Well, I'm afraid I'm gonna have to leave you here, Eddie,
但我真的...真的还想再多说一句
But I really... I really do want to do this again,
所以 记得给我电话 这份算是送你的了
So, call me, And, uh, that's on the house,
我不需要
I don't want it,
别不知足 知道这要多少钱吗
Don't be ungrateful, You know how much that costs?
800块 就这么一小粒
Eight hundred bucks, A pop,
别客气
You're welcome,
在回家的路上 我满脑子想得都是梅利莎
All the way home, I thought about Melissa.
她的生活怎么也会变得一团糟 她这么聪明
How could she be a failure, too? She'd been so smart.
比周围所有人都聪明
Smarter than anyone around her.
显然 当下的艾迪 和今天下午3点微醉的艾迪
Clearly, there was a direct link between this Eddie,
甚至和过往那个吐在老板桌上的
slightly drunk at 3:00 in the afternoon, and an earlier Eddie...
偷走将死姑妈止疼药的艾迪总有着直接联系
...vomiting on his boss's desk or stealing his dying aunt's Percocet.
所以无怪乎琳迪会弃我而去了
So who could blame Lindy for dumping me?
说到底 还能有多糟糕呢
In the end, how much worse could it get?
我什么人都不想见
I didn't want to see anybody.
尤其是房东那位恶毒的小妻子
Especially not my landlord's nasty young wife.
瓦莱利 才周二呢      听着 我受够了 明白吗
Valerie, Tuesday,        Look, Enough, OK?
是斯蒂文在处理房租 他也许吃你那套
Steve handles the rent, so you can feed your crap to him,
我突然有了摆脱她更好的理由
I suddenly had extra reason to get away from her.
我刚刚稀里糊涂地吞下了某种药物
I had thoughtlessly ingested a substance.
好像房租总不够便宜似的
Like the rent's not low enough!
关于这个药物的效果 我只从弗农那里
I had gotten remarkably little information from Vernon
获得了少得可怜的信息
about what this drug would do.
就算你现在骑车去送报也还来得及 我说真的
You could even be a bike messenger and come up with that, Really,
如果这是迷幻药又会怎样      真是毫无指望
What if it was a hallucinogen?        It's pathetic,
哦 上帝啊 看她没完没了的碎碎念...
Oh, my God. Listening to her rag...
如果我是你的话 早就直接跳窗了
If I were tripping, I'd jump out a fucking window.
嘿 你有没有在听我说
Hello? Are you listening to me?
你还不懂 是不是 你就等着滚去睡大街吧
Do you get it? You are gonna be out on the streets!
然后 我突然感觉到了
And then, I felt it.
之前我是盲目的 现在才终于看清了一切
I was blind, but now I see.
...赶紧给我走 都不敢看我的眼睛 知道为啥么
...running away! You can't even look at me, you know why?
因为你根本不算是个男人 根本就不是个男人
Because you're not even a man, You're not even a man!
不付房租 没有工作
You don't have rent! You don't have a job!
你怎么了      什么
What's wrong?        What?
你不喜欢我 我不怪你 在你眼里 我是个一无是处
You don't like me and I don't blame you, You see a self-defeating,
浪费生命 靠你丈夫施舍过日子的混球
energy-sucking piece of shit who's sponging off your husband,
你乐见我饮弹自尽
You're wishing I'd blow my brains out,
但我的存在并不该让你觉得不安 到底为什么呢
but my existence shouldn't make you this upset, What is it?
和你有什么关系      是法学院的课程不顺利吗
That's none of your business,        Something wrong at law school?
你怎么知道我在念法律
How do you know I'm in law school?
没有几个正常人会随身带着
People who aren't, usually don't carry around dry,
这种读来无趣 某位已故高院法官的迂腐之作
academically-constipated books about a dead Supreme Court justice,
你个变态 你...你跟踪我是不是
You're a creep, aren't you? You've been... You've been following me,
不是 我只是看到书而已      你才看到一个角
No, I just noticed the book,        You just saw the corner of it,
怎么能确定
How did you know that?
我之前看过 12年前 还在大学的时候
I'd seen it before. Twelve years ago in college.
坐在一个助教的沙发上
Sitting on the couch of a TA I was trying to make,
等着她沐浴归来
waiting for her to come back out of the bathroom,
希冀她能有一个保险套
hoping she'd have a condom.
突然之间这个信息就从潜意识中蹦了出来
Somehow my unconscious had served that up.
一段从未被我刻意记忆的片段
A memory I had never even recorded.
或者说 长久以来 我需要的只是一把钥匙
Or was it there the whole time and all I needed was the access?
如果你要写论文 这本书绝不是上佳选择
If you're writing a paper, that's not the book I'd use,
哈 谁问你意见了
Well, who asked you?
黑斯廷斯有自己的口述历史
Hastings has his oral history,
要是我 就会从那里着手
I'd start there,
有趣的是 基本而言 他就是个白痴
Interesting point, Grammatically, this guy was an idiot,
他曾经解雇的一位员工
which sort of gives credence to the theory
能写出他大部分的观点
that one of the clerks he had fired
这种家伙的理论 有谁愿意相信
actually wrote most of this guy's major opinions,
你可以谷歌一下那位雇员的子孙
You could Google the clerk's sons,
相信他们非常乐意和你交谈
they'd love to talk to you,
为他们父亲脱罪
Exonerate their dad,
也许能给到你一些无人知晓的东西...
That'd give you something that no one else has...
古怪博物馆展览的信息 半知半解的文字
Information from the odd museum show, a half-read article,
公共广播公司的某些文档...突然涌到我的额叶
some PBS documentary... it was all bubbling up in my frontal lobes,
自我混合成最绚丽最有用的信息鸡尾酒
mixing itself together into a sparkling cocktail of useful information.
她毫无机会      那你有什么建议呢
She didn't have a chance.        So, what are your suggestions?
我们确实为她的论文做了不少工作
We'd really worked on her paper, too.
但45分钟后 就演变成了另一种活动
In 45 minutes, it was a polished gem.
她显然也得到了满足
She was pleased.
家 但这里真的是我的家吗
Home. But it couldn't be my home, could it?
有谁能忍受住在这样的地方
Who would live like this?
真想一把火烧了这里
My first thought was Torch it.
但理智占了上风
But saner heads prevailed.
这算是什么毒品 完全没有上瘾后的混乱
What was this drug? I couldn't stay messy on it,
6个小时没抽一支烟 没有进食...
I hadn't had a cigarette in six hours, hadn't eaten,
那么是整洁和节制吗
so... abstemious and tidy?
这算什么呢 让人记忆力更强的毒品吗
What was this? A drug for people who wanted to be more anal retentive?
我不兴奋也不乖张 只是出人意料的清醒
I wasn't high, I wasn't wired. Just clear.
很清楚自己想做什么 该如何去做
I knew what I needed to do and how to do it.
第二天清晨 我小小探索了一下自己的大脑
The next morning, I sent a little probe down into my brain.
毫无任何的澎湃思绪和灵感闪现
No surge of brilliance came up to greet me.
短暂的光彩过后...我还是我
In short... I was back.
但是 有些东西却留了下来
But, something remained.
开玩笑吧你
You're kidding,
没有      居然有白纸黑字装订成册
No,        Words have appeared on paper,
是的      还能是出自你手
Yes,        Written by you,
只求你能看上三张
All you have to do is read three pages,
就花一个小时看上三张 然后...
Just read three pages in the next hour and...
...如果你没兴趣读下去 我就把预付款还你
...if you don't want to keep reading, I'll give you back the advance,
好吗
OK,
可以 艾迪      好的
OK, Eddie,        OK,
艾迪 回来了给我电话
Eddie, give me a call when you get in.
艾迪 我又看了40页 给我电话
Eddie, I'm 40 pages further in. Call me.
虽然有些小做作 不过我还在看
It's a little grandiose, but I'm still reading.
说吧 你怎么做到的
OK, how did you do this?
我真的很喜欢...一回来就给我电话 别忘了
I'd really like... Just call me the minute you get in. Call. OK?
谁啊      嘿 弗农 是我 艾迪
Who is it?        Hey, Vernon, it's Eddie,
哪个艾迪      嗯 我是莫莱
Eddie who?        Uh, Morra,
现在不是时候 艾迪
It's not a good time, Eddie,
呃 嘿 弗恩 我真的需要和你谈谈
Uh, hey, Vern, I really just need to talk to you,
嘿...哦...
Hey... Oh...
弗恩 出什么事了      别担心 我没事
Vern, what happened?        Don't worry about it, I'm fine,
好吧 艾迪 你还是有兴趣了
So, Eddie, You are interested after all,
这玩意儿太神奇了
That stuff's amazing,
如果你够聪明 就更有效果了
Works better if you're already smart,
弗恩 谁把你打成这样的
Vern, who did this to you?
相信我 你不会想知道的
Trust me, you don't want to know,
呃...
Uh...
那 这个叫什么来着      在市面上还没有名字
So, uh, what's it called?        Doesn't have a street name yet,
但是那些药剂师都叫它NZT 48
But the boys in the kitchen are calling it NZT 48,
"药剂师" 我不知道...
"The boys in the kitchen"? I don't...
听起来不怎么像是被食药局认可的药品啊 弗恩
That doesn't sound very FDA-approved, Vern,
食药局认可 说什么笑话呢
FDA-approved, that's a laugh,
你不会真相信了吧
You didn't really believe that shit, did ya?
好吧 现在是什么状况
OK, so what do we have here?
某种未知的 未经测试 有潜在危险的药片
Some unknown, untested, possibly dangerous drug
从某身份未明的实验室流落出来
scammed out of some unidentified lab somewhere
经由一个我多年未见 极不可信的家伙交到我手中
given to me by a highly unreliable guy I hadn't seen in years.
你还想要吗      是的 当然
So you want some more?        Yes, Definitely,
好吧 这个稍后再谈 但现在我需要有人帮个忙
All right, we'll talk about it, but I, uh, need a favor first,
显然 我现在这个样子是没法出门的
Obviously, I'm in no condition to go out right now, so,
我在想你能不能为我
I was wondering if you could pop down
去取一下送洗的西装
to the dry cleaners, grab my suit for me,
顺便再帮我弄点..早饭什么的
And maybe grab a little... A little breakfast for us,
他很清楚已经牢牢控制住了我
He knew he had me.
好吧
Sure,
从此刻开始 我很乐意成为他的专属小弟
From now on, I'd happily be his errand boy.
洗窗 擦马桶...
Wash his windows, scrub his toilet...
...任何事情我都愿意 只要能让那个
...anything I could do to get my hands on that little clear pill
升级版的艾迪重新回来
that would bring back... Enhanced Eddie.
弗恩
Vern?
弗恩...
哦 弗恩
Oh, Vern,
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey!
嘿
Hey!
911 请问有什么紧急情况      嘿 我想报警...
911, what's your emergency?        Hi, I need to report a...
...是一起谋杀
...a murder,
7B 是的
7B, yes,
好的 我不会的
OK, I won't,
像是等了一世纪 而我站得越久 看得越是明白
Took them forever. And the longer I stood there, the clearer I saw.
弗恩知道凶手是谁
Vern had known whoever had done this.
也明白他们在找的是什么
And one guess what they'd been looking for.
但他们找到了吗
But had they found it?
要命 如果你是自己开伙 那我这条命也交代了
Shit, if you ever cooked, I'd be dead, too,
我们是警察 请开门
Police Department! Open the door, please!
我们是警察 开门
Police Department! Open the door!
请立刻开门
Open the door, please!
我们是警察 开门
Police! Open the door!
我们进去 开门
Let's go! Open the door!
把手举起来      嘿
Let me see your hands,        Hey,
把手举起来      不是我 不 是我报的警
Let me see your hands!        No, no, I'm the one who called!
是我叫你们来的
I called you guys!
这么说 你们的关系不错咯 经常一起出入吗
So, you guys tight? Hang out a lot?
也不算是 他是我前妻的兄弟
No, my ex-wife's brother,
我也只是才和他在路上遇到
I just actually ran into him on the street
然后他让我上去坐坐...
and he asked me to come up to...
再买点毒品什么的吗
Buy some drugs?
不 不是的 什么意思      这家伙做什么的
No, no, What?        What did this guy do?
他...嗯 我不知道 他之前 嗯...
He... Uh, I don't know, He was, um...
听说他之前是个古董贩卖商
I heard that he was an antiques dealer?
贩卖商吗      是的 嗯 古董方面的 嗯...
A dealer?        Yeah, uh, antiques, Um...
好像是 维也纳风格的...
Like, uh, Viennese kinda, um...
...椅子什么的
...chairs and stuff,
就像是 你知道的 那种圈腿椅之类的
Like, you know, like curlicue leg things,
你好
Yeah?
没错 是有一位艾德华・莫莱
That is correct, An Edward Morra,
他就在这里
He's here,
受害者的妹妹
Victim's sister,
我已经有10年没有听到她的声音了
I hadn't heard her voice in ten years.
艾迪      梅利莎
Eddie?        Melissa?
你当时在场吗      是的...
You were there?        Um...
我之前正好在街上遇到他 所以 是的...
Just before, I had run into him on the street and, uh... yeah,
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
我都不觉得奇怪 他是卷入了件麻烦里
I wish I was more surprised. He was involved in some stuff.
我不应该多说的
I'd better not say any more.
是的 没错 这也许是个好主意
No, no, that's probably a good idea,
那么 嗯...也许我们应该见个面什么的
So, uh... We should probably, uh, meet or something, right?
不用了 我还要处理丧礼还有各种乱七八糟的事
No, I gotta do the funeral and God knows what else.
我只是...
I just...
我们不能见面 好吗
We can't meet, OK?
好吧 嗯 我只是...
Right, Well, I'll just...
那葬礼上见吧
I guess I'll just see you at the funeral then,
不了 我不想 别这样 再联系吧 好吗
No. I don't want that. Please don't. I'll call you at some point, OK?
等事情都结束了      好的 那就这样吧
When this is over.        OK, all right,
好的
OK.
要知道 现在有些事情还不明朗
You know, something doesn't gel here,
留下你的电话 稍后也许会再联系你
Write down your number, I may need to contact you later,
值得冒这个风险吗
Worth the risk?
如果是你 会如何呢
What would you do?
弗恩留下的现金 加上一些前所未有潮涌的冲动
Vern's cash, combined with an unprecedented surge of motivation,
促使我在4天里面完成了一整本小说
enabled me to finish the book in four days.
一天一片
A tablet a day
每天的时间都是如此有限而珍贵
and what I could do with my day was limitless.
我在3天里学会了弹奏钢琴
I learned to play the piano in three days.
数学变得有用
Math became useful.
而充满奇趣
And fun.
全跟
I'm all in,
只是半知半解 已足以让我熟练运用一门新语言
Even half-listening to any language, I became fluent.
那你觉得莎士比亚抖的小包袱其实很普通咯
So that Shakespeare's catchiness belies mediocrity?
毫无争辩之意
There's no arguing with you,
这种感觉太棒了
This was great.
听我说 妈妈 关于海伦姑妈的肿瘤 我做了些研究
So, Mom, I've been doing a little research on Aunt Helen's tumor,
非常明确的一点就是
And it's totally clear that
任何罹患此类家族性腺瘤性息肉的人
anybody with familial adenomatous polyposis
应当接受含铂类双重
should be supplementing platinum-based doublet regiments
二十碳五烯酸补充治疗
with eicosapentaeonic acid,
突然之间我变得无所不知 无所不晓
I suddenly knew everything. About everything.
当然 这只是一个短期的刺激
Well, sure, you get a short-term spike,
但过快的增长
but wouldn't that rapid expansion
是否会导致两年内股票的彻底贬值呢
devalue that stock completely in two years?
不会 因为安全机制的存在
No, because there are safeguards,
限制了侵略性过度膨胀?
Against aggressive over-expansion?
没有用的 在人性中不存在所谓的安全机制
There aren't, Because there are no safeguards in human nature,
过犹不及通常带来失败
We're wired to overreach,
回顾整个历史 看看那些曾颠覆世界的国家
Look at history, all the countries that ever ruled the world,
葡萄牙曾拥有大量傲视当世的海军
Portugal with this big massive navy,
现在呢 只剩下了腌鳕鱼和廉价保险套
All they got now are salt cod and cheap condoms,
更别说曾经的日不落帝国了
And the Brits?
只能蜗居在潮湿阴冷的岛国
Now they're just sitting on a dank little island
为明天的西装忧心不已
fussing over their suits,
为什么就没人愿意停下思考一下
No one's stopping and thinking,
"嘿 我们已经做得很好了
"Hey, we're doing pretty well,
占领了法国 波兰还有瑞士银行里巨大的存款
We got France, we got Poland, we got a big Swiss bank account,
为什么还要大冷天的跑去侵略什么俄罗斯
You know what? Let's not invade Russia in the winter,
踏实回家 举杯庆祝 依靠这些利息颐养天年吧"
Let's go home, let's pop a beer, and let's live off the interest,"
说的没错
Yeah,
这些所思所感如潮水般从我脑中涌出
My brain was just pouring this stuff out.
所有我曾经读过 听过 看过的东西
Everything I had ever read, heard, seen
都变成了条理分明 随时可用的观点
was now organized and available.
就是这里 你到了
Here it is. Here you go.
艾迪 嘿 听我说 我想你应该在做一些投资
Eddie, Hey, Listen, I'm sure you have a portfolio,
当然如果没有的话 我非常乐意和你一起工作
but if you don't, I'd be very interested in working with you,
好的 凯文
OK, Kevin,
我结交了新朋友 应邀前往海滩
I made some new friends who invited me to the beach.
当然不是近在眼前的海滩
The beach was not nearby.
曾经的战战兢兢和羞涩腼腆 都离我而去
All my fear, all my shyness, gone.
他们做了四次基本审查...
They've done four basic trials...
但只是懒散度日并不足够
But mere lounging wasn't enough.
唯一麻烦是 如果无法继续前进
Only problem? If I wasn't moving forward,
我一定会承受不了而崩溃
I felt like I was going to explode.
快过来 这里太美了 是不是
Come up here because it's beautiful, right?
有人想试试看吗      你疯了吧
Anybody ever jump?        Are you crazy?
他真的会跳的      别扯了
He's gonna do it,        He's not gonna do it,
哦 上帝
Oh, my God!
哦
Oh!
啊
Ah!
就在此刻我有了主意
And then I began to form an idea.
我突然明白了该做的到底是什么
Suddenly, I knew exactly what I needed to do.
无关创造 更无关书本
It wasn't writing. It wasn't books.
远甚于这些
It was much bigger than that.
但我需要足够的钱来完成这一切
But it would take money to get there.
在下游市场 没有人能赚到足够的资本
In a down market, no one was making much.
同样这些人也没有NZT
But no one had NZT.
以最乐观的预计
In an optimistic scenario,
这种自然的收益只能反映
gains of that nature merely would reflect
经济的增长 而并不会造成任何障碍的产生...
growth in the economy and would not pose an obstacle...
用弗恩剩下的最后800块 在一天之内赚了2000
Armed with Vern's last $800, I made 2,000 in a day.
第二天 变成了7500
Next day, 7,500.
还是太慢 我需要更多的资金
It was too slow. I'd need more capital.
但银行不会贷款给我这样的人
But banks weren't lending to guys like me.
嘿 利夫
Hey, Liev,
你要找的人就坐在角落里
That's your man in the corner back there,
好的
Yeah,
利夫应该已经和你说了 我想找笔短期借贷
So, uh, Liev told you that I'm looking for a short-term loan?
是的 我让利夫拉倒吧
Yeah, and I told Liev forget it,
为什么
Why?
因为我不认识你 更他妈的开始不喜欢你了
Because I don't see you before and I don't fucking like you already,
所以我为什么要借你十万呢
Why do I give you $100,000?
因为...
Because...
...我有能力在四天之内让这些钱涨五倍
...I quintupled my money four days in a row,
这么说 你有内幕消息吗
So you got a fix on the game,
不 不算是
No, not a fix,
我只是运用一些计算法则得出了某些定式
I was able to calculate certain patterns using algorithms,
如果你看下第四栏的话 是第一...
If you look at column four, this was the first...
你说的没错
You're good,
我是有消息
OK, it's a fix,
要知道 你们这种人总会被逮住的
Yeah, you know, all you people get caught,
到时候你要怎么办
What are you gonna do then?
至少我没有什么写有你大名的黑名册
Well, it's not as if I have a black book with your name in it,
如果你关心的是这个问题
if that's what you're talking about,
此外 我有很强的预感
And besides, I get the strong feeling
我绝不愿意轻易让你失望
that you're not somebody I want to disappoint,
别起来 我说了别起来
Don't get up, I said don't get up,
坐好了      嘿 好的
Sit down!        Hey, OK,
拿了这钱 你的小命就是我的了      好的
OK, you take this, you mine,        OK,
听好了 如果到时候不还钱 后果你很清楚吧
You understand? You don't pay, you know what we do?
我会直接腰斩了你
I cut you at waist,
剥了你的皮 绑到你脑袋顶上去
Peel your skin up over your head and tie knot in it,
窒息这玩意儿 你绝不会想死那么难看
You don't die from this, You suffocate,
好的      祝你好运了
OK,        Good luck,
我的新朋友 凯文・道尔 教会了我
My new friend, Kevin Doyle, showed me how you could leverage
如何在当日交易公司 让一块钱变成两块半
two and a half times your cash at the day trading firm.
一周以来 我不断的增加用量
I'd been upping the dose for over a week.
似乎确实缩短了我的学习曲线
It seemed to cut my learning curve.
为什么要买这个 他们的CEO刚刚受到控告
Why are you buying that? The CEO was just indicted,
但并不是因为他贿赂的事情
But not for the big fat defense contract he bribed his way into,
还会上涨的 下周就会宣布
That's still on, Should be announced next week,
我刚刚黑入了系统 重新启动
I was jacked in. Booted up.
在周末 我的经纪人账户
At the end of the week, my brokerage account
已经超过了两百万
contained over two million dollars.
消息传得很快
Word quickly got out.
19条新信息
You have 19 messages.
4个工作机会 银行提高了我的信用额度
Four job offers, my bank raising my line of credit,
纽约邮报专访报道
a reporter from the New York Post,
一定给我回电 莫莱先生
Really call me back, Mr. Morra.
没有人能在这么短的时间内累计财富
No one makes money that fast.
不管你是否出现 这篇文章登定了
This article's gonna get written with or without you.
最终 凯文・道尔带来了好消息
And finally, Kevin Doyle trying to sound casual.
艾迪 我和我的老板谈过你的事情
Eddie, I was talking you up to my boss
最不可能的事情居然成真了 老兄
and, well, the impossible happened, bud.
我们给你安排了和卡尔・范隆的碰面
We got you a meeting with Carl Van Loon.
卡尔・范隆要见你吗
Carl Van Loon wants to meet you?
显然是有这么回事      但你不并擅长金融行业
Apparently so,        But you're not in the finance game,
你能帮卡尔・范隆做什么
What can you do for Carl Van Loon?
你什么时候学的意大利语
Since when do you speak Italian?
哦 自我提升的几个月吧
Oh, Self-improvement month,
大概是谁点醒了我吧
I guess somebody gave me a wake up call,
希望不是因为我
I hope you didn't do it for me,
不 我只是希望能向你道歉 琳
No, I just wanted to apologize to you, Lin,
让你明白 我的自我毁灭
And let you know that apparently my capacity for self-sabotage
并非无下限
wasn't boundless after all,
而我真正想知道的是 为什么要这样容忍我
The real question is, why did you ever put up with me?
因为那时候我爱你
I was in love with you,
嗯 书什么时候出版
So, when does the book come out?
明年吧 你的新助理怎么样
Next year, How's your new assistant?
还挺好的      那就好
She's good,        Good,
嗯      好的
Yeah,        Yeah,
那你 嗯 有没有新...
And, uh, are you gonna get a new...
听我说...你能来 我真的很高兴
You know... I'm really happy you're here with me,
我为你骄傲 而且...
I'm proud of you, And...
...更有些威胁感
...a little intimidated,
我们又重新开始了
We started up again.
她家
Her place.
我家
My place.
任何地方
Basically every place.
"在3天火热的交易中
"In a sizzling three days of trading,
这位莫莱先生颠覆了整个市场
the unknown Mr. Morra trumped the market,
引用某位对冲基金经理的评论
prompting one top hedge fund manager to comment:
'他就是霍迪尼 我们这个时代的预言家'"
'He's Houdini, He's a prophet of our times,"'
好了 给我 快给我啦
OK, give me that, Give me that!
"他是上帝"      晚点过来吗
"He's God"?        You coming over later?
不行 我可没有钥匙
I can't, I don't have a key,
哦 也是
Oh, that's right,
那我能拿回来吗      嗯...别想
Can I have it back?        Uh... Nope,
不行吗      我想说的是 一定是要原来那把吗
No?        I mean, does it have to be that key?
不能有一把新钥匙吗
Can it be a new key?
我们家的新钥匙
To our place?
这代价可不小啊      你是说我不够务实
It would be cost effective,        And you say I'm not practical,
我送你去上班吧
Can I walk you to work?
看什么呢 亲爱的
Whatcha doing, hon?
没事
Nothing,
该睡觉了
You should sleep,
明天不是还要去见范隆吗
Isn't your Van Loon meeting tomorrow?
艾迪
Eddie?
你还好吗
Are you OK?
你在这里干什么
What are you doing out here?
你上次是什么时候吃的饭
When's the last time you ate something?
看这是谁啊 邮报上的文章不错啊 老兄
There he is, Nice article in the Post, buddy,
好吧 他就在过来的路上
OK, he is on his way,
现在 听好了 这个人反复无常
Now, be warned, He's mercurial,
前一秒 可能是你最好的朋友
One minute, your best friend,
而下一秒 就对你避之不及
the next, you're a leper,
他需要的是最为直接的答复
And he needs direct answers,
任何的试探犹豫都会让你错失良机
Anything tentative and you've lost him forever,
我们应该排练一下的
I think we should rehearse a few scenarios,
凯文 我还在吃东西
I'm eating, Kevin,
嘿 你就是来吃东西的吗
Hey, are you up for this?
你确定吗 我可是冒了很大风险
You sure? 'Cause I got a little bit on the line here,
来点吐司吧
Have a toast point,
是卡尔・范隆      是卡尔・范隆
It's Carl Van Loon,        That's Carl Van Loon,
财富的象征
He's worth a fortune,
嘿 约翰      嘿 卡尔 见到你很高兴
Hey, John,        Hey, Carl, Good to see you,
你好啊      艾迪
How are ya?        Eddie,
那么 艾迪・莫莱
So, Eddie Morra,
你的秘密是什么      药物
What's your secret?        Medication,
我在服用某种特殊药物
I'm on special medication,
好的
OK,
某种特殊的复合配方
Well, it's a formula with a complex method,
当然 调研 大量的调研也是其中一部分
But, of course, research was a component, Massive research,
我清楚了解自己购买公司的每一丝架构
I knew every helix of every scrap of DNA in every company I bought,
我办公室的资料堆积如山 知道这意味着什么吗
Papers stacked like the Himalayas in my office, and you know what?
股价上涨      说对了一点
The stocks went up,        By a hair,
没错 股价是在上涨 但谁愿意为某个
Sure, the stocks rose, but who wants to do all that work
毫无远见的领导者工作
for a shitty little uptake?
你想要的并不是
It's not the visceral kind of spike you want
短期的持有或是增长...
in short term holdings so...
...抛弃所有的统计数据
...I dispensed with all the hard statistics
我直接在市场传闻中捕捉需要的信息
and I went right to the rumor mill,
你的股票都是这样买进的吗
So you bought your stocks based on what?
街边的小道消息?
The tom-toms beating in the street?
自然 股价的高低并非真正基于公司的运营状况
Sure, Share prices aren't really based on how a company works,
更多的是对群众心理的把握
It's about how mass psychology works,
所以如果我发现了股价预测的某种计算方式
So, if I found certain algorithms in the perception of the stock...
模式识别 看来这就是你骗人的万灵油咯
Pattern recognition, That's your snake oil,
但 并非所有人都能理解这种模式
Well, not everybody understands the patterns,
这让我更具灵性
And that gave me a little bit more of an uptake,
但这也不过是拿不出手的小把戏
but it's just a parlor trick,
然后 我打算另辟蹊径
So then, I went on to door number three,
你是暗示自己已经找到了某种终端公式吗
Are you really implying that you have some sort of ultimate formula?
好吧 10天里 从一万两千到两三百万的累积
Well, from 12,000 to 2,3 million in ten days,
我自然有公式 皮尔斯先生      夸大妄想
I do have a formula, Mr. Pierce,        Delusions of grandeur,
我并非夸大妄想
I don't have delusions of grandeur,
我有的是宏伟建筑的详细计划
I have an actual recipe for grandeur,
我不知道你是谁 也不清楚你的把戏
I don't know who you are, Eddie, or what you game is,
但有一点我很肯定
but I'm sure of one thing,
你并不是我会任而用之的人
You don't work in my world,
我太熟悉所谓的投资人
I'm up to my ass with investment guys
你不像他们是惶恐不安
and you don't have their half-terrified,
和妄自尊大的混合体...
half-cocky line of crap which is...
...但这并不意味着我会更欣赏你
...not to say that I like yours any better,
但显而易见的是 你以一种
But you obviously pick your stocks
我从未见识过的方式选择股票
in a way which I haven't seen before,
看看这些公司 然后告诉我你的想法
Take a look at these companies and tell me what you think,
现在吗      是的 你可以慢慢来
Right now?        Yeah, Take your time,
当然
Sure,
这些公司并不是问题所在 对吗
These companies aren't the question, are they?
解释下
Explain,
除非你两边都有插手
Unless you're playing both sides of the fence,
控制住整个能源市场 但是 不对
Control the whole power enchilada, but, no,
这些公司并不足以让你入主
these companies wouldn't get you there in emerging markets,
你还必须...哦 喔哦
You would have to... Oh, Whoa,
一定是了 你深思熟虑过的某种合并大案子
This must be some big-ass merger you're contemplating,
真正有能力和范隆合作的
And there's really only one company with enough bling
只有一家公司
to justify a merger with Van Loon and Associates,
你以为是在和谁说话
Who have you been talking to?
哦 我只是将线索连接
Oh, I'm just connecting the dots,
汉克・阿特伍德真的会同意吗
Is Hank Atwood really gonna go for it?
嗯 你要么是个惊人的诈骗艺术家
Well, you're an amazing con artist,
要么就是个聪明绝顶的年轻人
or you're a very smart young man,
行了 你们两个合作?
I mean, come on, The two of you together?
整个世界就会像奥利弗・特维斯特一样
The whole world would have to come begging for energy
端着破碗向你们乞讨能源
like Oliver Twist and his bowl of gruel,
你现在是倒退了 还看出什么
Now you're going backwards, What else you got?
预言 这行不通的      为什么
A prediction, It won't come off,        Why's that?
除非能放弃利比亚      真的吗
You'd have to back off Libya,        Really?
好吧 你不会想从搭你便车的笨蛋那里
Well, you don't want to hear this from some schmuck
听到这些信息
who needs a ride home,
好吧 你赢了
All right, you get your shot,
明早10点圣瑞吉酒店见
Meet me tomorrow at the Saint Regis at ten
让我看看这位贪婪的搭便车的小笨蛋
and tell me how the gutsy little schmuck who needs a ride home
会如何重组这些交易 你最好做好充分的准备
would re-structure these deals, And you'd better be prepared,
悉听尊便
I'm at your disposal,
你不会真住在这里吧
You don't really live here, do you?
嗯...艰苦朴素通常不怎么喜闻乐见
Well... Spartans weren't big on amenities,
是的 他们通常会摔得很惨
Yeah, and they eventually got their asses kicked,
我没有进屋 更想四处走走 消化再吸收
I didn't go in. I wanted to walk, move, digest, ingest.
生活中就是有这样的时候
There are moments in life...
你清楚自己离成功只有一步之遥
moments when you know you've crossed a bridge.
你过去的失败已成过往
Your old life is over.
而范隆就是我的那一步 我终于走到了这里
Van Loon was my bridge. I finally had my shot.
华尔街会提供所需的一切 但我又能走多远呢
Wall Street would provide my nest egg, but then how far could I go?
CEO 全球力量 也许还能是总统
CEO? A global force? Maybe President.
是到了有人来撼动这个世界 完成事业的时候了
Time somebody shook up the free world and got things done.
突然之间...
Suddenly...
又是一个跳跃 我怎么走过了20个街区呢
It was another skip. How had I gone the last 20 blocks?
又是10个 然后...
I got another ten blocks. And then...
...又到了住宅区
...I was way uptown.
这是哪个酒吧
What bar was this?
...黑色的油画布 这样他们能将所有的颜料...
...black canvas and then they would just drop all the paint...
是的 你有没有见过...
Yeah, Did you ever meet...
...然后我就去吃午饭了 回家...
...and then I actually went there and had lunch, I went back,
我的朋友都财源滚滚...
My friends are rolling...
听说你很喜欢派对
I heard you like to party.
嘿 小心点      嘿 嘿 别激动
Hey, watch it,        Hey, hey! Take it easy!
打架? 我应该不会的
A fight? Don't know how to fight.
不过 真的不会吗
Or do I?
用手指勾伸入嘴内部
You use the fishhook action to get inside the mouth.
就像这样
Like this.
攻击敏感区域 眼睛 咽喉 腹股沟
Attack the sensitive areas. The eyes, the throat, the groin.
一旦得手 不要停止
If you are hit, do not stop.
你的坚持不懈会让袭击者退缩
Your persistence will discourage your attacker.
让对手失去平衡
Off-balancing your opponent
并利用他的冲力 带倒他
and then using his momentum, take him down.
当一切静止的时候
When it finally stopped,
我完全无法拼凑出生命中过去的18个小时
I couldn't account for the last 18 hours of my life.
嘿 是我 我本以为你会来
Hey, it's me. I thought you were coming over.
你还好吗 接到留言给我电话
Is everything OK? Call me when you get this.
即便没有NZT 我仍决定尝试研究范隆的文件
Even off NZT, I decided to give Van Loon's files a shot.
却发现根本就是天书一般的存在
They were hieroglyphs.
喂      凯文 我是艾迪
Hello?        Kevin, this is Eddie.
艾迪      听我说
Eddie?        Listen,
今天我去不了了      你在说什么
I can't make the meeting today.        What are you talking about?
我今天去不了 我病了
I can't come in today, I'm sick,
哦 你不会现在就得了流感吧
Yeah, well you can't have the flu right now,
他不会再给我们第二次机会的
He'll never give you this chance again,
我知道 听着 只是...还有数据要分析
I know, listen, I just... I have all this data to analyze...
那你昨天去干了什么
What have you been doing for the last day?
凯文 我...      你不明白吗 这是对你的测试
Kev, I...        Don't you get it? This is your test,
是的 我明白 但此时此刻我无法通过这个测试
Yeah, well, I can't pass the test right now,
如果你不行 我要怎么办
And how am I gonna look if you don't?
我明白 听我说 我只是...      你安静听我说
I know, listen, I just...        Sh, Listen to me,
收拾好你自己 准时来赴约
Pull yourself together, Get down to the meeting,
好吧 好吧 我去 我会去的
OK, OK, I'll be there, I'll be there,
嘿 你好      艾迪
Hey, how are ya?        Eddie,
很高兴再次见到你
Good to see you again,
请坐
Sit down,
你对汉克・阿特伍德了解多少
What do you know about Hank Atwood?
阿特伍德 嗯...
Atwood, um...
他是个传统叛逆者 嗯...
He's an iconoclast, um...
拥有大半科罗拉多州的财富
Owns about half of Colorado,
这就是你精心准备的结果吗 艾迪
So this is prepared, Eddie?
嗯...
Uh...
算是阿特伍德入门知识吗
Is this Atwood 101?
还有谁不认识阿特伍德的吗
Doesn't everybody know about Atwood?
他两年前在哪里
Where was he two years ago?
嗯      哪里都不是
Hm?        Nowhere,
两年前他还没在福布斯的榜上
Two years ago he wasn't even on Forbes' radar,
巨大的飞跃 不是吗
That was a great leap forward, right?
我看不懂这家伙 他就这么凭空窜出 强势有力
I'm baffled by this guy, He comes out of nowhere so strong,
在我还没机会深入敌营之前 就让我疲于应对了
Has me on the run before I can even get to anybody in his camp,
在两项产业上 给了我沉重一击
Beats me out of two properties,
投资了毫无原油资源 更是我从未触及的领域
investing in countries with no oil, Places I'd never go near...
我们现在位于一家酒店的门口
We're here in front of the hotel where a woman,
昨晚 一位名叫玛利亚・温贝里的女性
identified as Maria Winberg,
被证实死于酒店房间
was found dead in her room last night,
成为不法行为的受害者
a victim of foul play.
温贝里女士是知名的社交名媛 模特...
Ms. Winberg was a well-known socialite and model...
...更因其乐衷慈善而誉满全城
...but was also known for her dedicated charity work around the city.
警方花费了数个小时询问酒店雇员及顾客
Police spent hours questioning hotel staff and patrons
有目击证人证实目睹一名男人离开现场...
and an eyewitness reported seeing a man leaving the scene...
...能否帮我说服他可以和我合作
... help me convince him that I can raise his game,
你有什么意见吗
Got any ideas?
你怎么看
What do you think?
酒店内设置了足够的监控录像...
Hotel has adequate security cameras...
艾迪 你不是这种人吧 是不是
You're not one of those kind of guys, are you Eddie?
房间里摆个电视就能让你思想分散吗
We lose you if there's a screen in the room?
我们的世界正在悄无声息地发生改变
These are tectonic plates that are shifting right under us,
抱歉 容我暂离片刻
Pardon me, one second.
可能吗 我杀人了?
Was it possible? Could I have killed someone?
真是我干的?
Was it even me?
艾迪? 我是梅利莎
Eddie? This is Melissa.
弗农不会给过你什么吧
Listen, Vernon hasn't been giving you anything, has he?
那东西很危险
Because that stuff is dangerous.
梅利莎?
Melissa?
梅利莎 我们能找地方见面吗
Melissa, hey, do you think that we can meet somewhere?
我需要和你谈谈      我们正谈着呢
I really need to talk to you,        We're talking now.
不是这样的 中午在...
No, no, let's meet at, uh...
格兰特的比利餐厅碰头怎么样
Billy's on Grant at noon?
你不能见我      不 不...
You can't see me, Eddie.        No, no...
拜托 艾迪      拜托 来吧 我...
Eddie, please.        Please, please come, please come, I...
这很重要 我需要弄明白你的意思
It's important, I really need to know what you're talking about,
我意识到也许还有其他人知道NZT的存在
I realized that there were other people who might know about NZT.
弗农的其他客户
Vernon's other clients.
你好      你好
Hi.        Yeah, hi,
我想找一下杰瑞・布莱迪
may I please speak with Jerry Brady?
杰瑞住院了      他怎么了
Jerry's in the hospital.        He's what?
他的病情非常不乐观
Yeah, he's not doing well at all.
你好 请问保罗・卡普兰在吗      不 他不在
Yeah, hello, is Paul Kaplan there?        Uh, no. No, he's not.
保罗三天前去世了
Uh, Paul passed away three days ago.
我的天 请节哀
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry,
起初他感觉头疼 随后在工作中倒下
Yeah, he started getting headaches, then he collapsed at work.
现在他在重症监护室
Now he's in the ICU.
请代我问候他 谢谢
OK, please give him my best, Thank you,
我电话问过的人当中 三个死了 其余病重
Of all the people I called... three were dead and the rest were sick.
喂 喂
Hello? Hello?
小心点 哥们儿!
Watch it, man!
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
喂!
Hey!
快走! 快走!
Go! Go!
艾迪
Eddie,
梅利莎
Melissa,
嗨
Hey,
别说我容光焕发 因为我知道
Don't tell me I look good, 'cause I know,
自己不希望你见到我这鬼样子
I didn't want you to see me this way,
你看上去挺好
You look good,
我...
Oh, I, uh...
是啊 我重新振作了起来
Yeah, I sorta got myself together,
NZT就有这个效果
NZT will do that to you,
你这是什么意思      我的意思是 我也吃了
What do you mean?        I mean, I took it, too,
弗农什么也没告诉你 对吗
Vernon didn't tell you any of this, did he?
没有
No,
他和我提起这种神奇新药的时候
Well, when he told me about this amazing new drug,
我正处于人生谷底 而它 确实太神了
I was like, down the hatch, And it was, It was amazing,
我45分钟就读完了布莱恩・格林的"宇宙的琴弦"
I read Brian Greene's The Elegant Universe in 45 minutes
并且能够理解消化
and I understood it,
转瞬之间我的工作效率疯狂提升
My work rate increased just insanely overnight
我老板为此恨死我了
and my boss started to hate me,
上面把他的位置给了我 然后...我开始感到恐惧
They offered me his job and then... and then I got scared,
为什么      为什么 因为我不蠢
Why?        Why? Because I'm not stupid,
没人能负担如此高速的大脑运转而不崩溃
Nobody can operate at that level of mental activity and not crash,
我停止了服药
I stopped taking it,
然后呢      然后我就病了 头疼
And?        And I got sick, Headaches,
呕吐 于是我又去找弗农
Throwing up, So I went back to Vernon,
他告诉我所有服用的人都在陆续死去
He told me about all the people that were dying,
你吃了多少 艾迪
How much have you been taking, Eddie?
吃了很多
I've been taking a lot,
那也许...也许他们解决了那个缺陷 也许...
Well, maybe... maybe they've worked out the bugs, Maybe...
也许那不是同一批药
Maybe this is a different batch,
也许吧      你现在没服用了 对吧
Yeah,        You're off it right now, aren't you?
先把你的故事讲完
Just finish your story,
...我没再服用 也就活了下来
...I didn't take any more and I didn't die,
但过了一段时间 我发现自己再也无法
But after a while, I realized I couldn't concentrate on anything
集中精力超过十分钟
for longer than ten minutes,
我...我赶不上截稿日期 懒惰 拖拖拉拉
I, uh... I missed deadlines, got lazy, slow, so slow,
那是两年前的事了
That was two years ago,
而我到现在都还没恢复过来
And I haven't been the same since,
你的药还有剩余吗 很好
Do you have some left? Good,
回家马上吃了
You go home and you take it,
不要停止服药
You take the dose down, but you don't just stop,
停止服药你就死定了
You'll die if you just stop,
逐渐降低服药量 否则头疼只是噩梦的开始
Try to taper off, otherwise the headaches are just the beginning,
我得走了
I have to go,
你知道谁发明了这个药吗      我不知道
Do you know who makes it?        I don't know,
我得走了
I have to go,
该死 听我说 听我说 好吧
Oh, shit, Listen, listen, listen, Listen, listen, listen... OK,
你忘记我的事了?      没有 没有
You forget about me, huh?        No, no, no, no,
12点你没出现
12:00 and you're not here,
我现在来了      很好
I'm here now, Oh!        Good,
快点 赶紧走      我可以给你开支票
Come on, get going,        I could write you a check,
支票 支票 你脑子进水了?
Check, Check, Are you out of your mind?
你以为我是干什么的 做正经融资的吗
What do you think I am? Some financial institution?
好吧 你说得对 我们只需要去家银行
All right, You're right, Look, we just need to go to a bank...
那是什么玩意儿
What do you got there?
那是什么      只是阿司匹林
What is it?        No, it's just aspirin,
看上去可不像阿司匹林 是好东西 对吧
Don't look like no aspirin I ever see, It's something good, huh?
我感觉不错 那到底是什么
I feel good, man, What's in this stuff?
只是维生素和阿司匹林
It's just, uh, vitamins and aspirin,
纯属胡说八道 艾迪小子
You full of shit, Eddie baby,
琳迪 我没让他进来 但是...
Lindy, I wouldn't have let him in, but...
抱歉      泰勒 抱歉先挂了
I'm sorry...        Tyler, I gotta go,
我病了
I'm sick,
我不该来的... 抱歉 但我走不回家了
I shouldn't... I'm sorry, I couldn't make it home,
我们马上去医院      不 不 不
Let's get you to a hospital,        No, no, no, no, no, I don't need...
我需要你去拿...
I need you to get...
非常简单 我需要服药
It's really simple, babe, I need my pills,
艾迪 什么药      我不...宝贝 这一言难尽
Eddie, what pills?        I don't... Babe, it's complicated,
你在服什么药 吸毒吗
What are you taking? Are you on drugs?
它们是...它是...
They're... it's...
我别无选择 只好向琳迪坦白一切
I had no choice. I told Lindy everything.
你所有的精力 注意力
So all this energy of yours, all this focus...
...都源自一种药物
...has been a drug,
它应该是合法的
Well, it was supposed to be legal,
我还有...一批存货
I have a... a supply stashed,
你希望我去帮你拿来
You want me to go get it,
不 不 不 我自己去拿      给我钥匙
No, No, no, no, I'm gonna go get it,        Give me your keys,
我这就去你的公寓
I'll go to your apartment,
不在...我公寓里 我把它转移了
It's not... in my apartment, I moved it,
好吧 那你藏在哪里了
OK, so where did you move it?
藏在我家里
In my house,
真是不可思议
Unbelievable,
喂 你拿到了吗
Hey, have you got it?
是的
Yeah,
有人在跟踪我
There's someone following me,
你确定吗
Are you sure?
是的 他上了我后面那辆出租车
Yeah, He got into the cab behind me
从头到尾跟着我
and he's making every turn I'm making,
宝贝 报警      你能甩掉他吗
Baby, call the cops,        Can you go around him?
亲爱的 怎么了
Babe, what's happening?
堵在路上了
We're stopped dead,
他从车上下来了
He's getting out,
艾迪 他走过来了
Eddie, he's walking over here,
琳迪?
Lindy?
我的天!
Oh, God!
救命! 救命!
Help! Help!
这个男人...他在跟踪我!
This man's... This man's chasing me!
他跟着我出了我家 可我不认识他
He followed me from my building, I don't know him,
拜托!      喂 老小子 别找她麻烦!
Please!        Yo, buddy, let's leave her alone!
你聋了吗 我说别找她麻烦!
Are you deaf? I said leave her alone,
喂 老小子 你这是想把我惹毛吗
Hey, buddy, are you trying to piss me off?
你在干什么 混蛋?
What are you doing, man?
你没挂吧      我没挂 怎么了
Are you still there?        Yeah, I'm here, What happened?
我被困住了 他迟早找到我
I'm stuck, He'll find me,
好 别说话了 别动
OK, stop talking. Don't move.
他杀了两个人      什么
He killed two guys.        What?
他也会杀了我的      不 不 不会的
He's gonna kill me, too,        No, no, no...
他能看见你吗
Can he see you?
看不见
No,
暂时还看不见
Not yet,
我不知道要怎么办才好
I don't know what to do,
好 我要你打开袋子吃一颗药
OK, I need you to go into the bag and take one of the pills,
为什么
Why?
因为那样你就知道该怎么办了 吃了你就明白了
Because you'll know what to do. You'll take it and then you'll know.
他手里有刀 艾迪 我不觉得自己能刀下逃生
He's got a knife, Eddie, I can't think my way out of a knife,
听我的话 30秒钟后药就会生效
Just listen to me, It'll come on in 30 seconds,
然后你再思考要怎么脱身 药就有这个功效
And you'll think your way out, That's what it does,
他越走越近了
He's getting closer,
琳迪 我爱你
Lindy, I love you,
嗨
Hey!
现在转过来...
Now turn to me...
你要干什么!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
啊!      爸爸!
Ah!        Daddy!
艾迪 给
Eddie, Here,
没事了
It's gonna be OK,
我们得离开这里 艾迪?
We've got to get out of here, Eddie?
你没事吧
You OK?
没事
Yeah,
对于那件事我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry about what happened,
我希望你明白我们再也不会经历那种事了
I want you to know that you never, ever have to go through that again,
因为我会照顾好我们俩的
'cause I can take care of us now,
我相信你可以
I'm sure you can,
我能保证我俩的安全 我又恢复了 好吗
I can make us safe, I'm back, OK?
谁恢复了 艾迪      我呀
Who's back, Eddie?        Me,
不 那不是你
No, It's not you,
你以前不是这个样子      我依旧是我 琳迪
You were different before,        I'm still the same person, Lin,
而我不是了 药效发作的时候
I wasn't, when I was on it,
我做出了自己平时绝对做不到的事
I did things I would never do,
那些事救了你的命      但那本不是我能做到的
Those things saved your life,        But they weren't me,
是的 是你做到的 药是那样发挥...
Yes, they were, No, the way it works...
我知道它是怎么发挥功效的
I know how it works, I get it,
我完全明白 你觉得自己所向无敌
I totally get it, You feel invincible,
它能让我们取得多大的成功 你根本无法想象
Where it will take us, Lin, you can't even imagine,
我们能做到的事情 我们一年后能成为怎样的人
The things we'll be able to do, Where we'll be a year from now,
我们终将能过上的那种上等人的生活
The kind of life that we'll finally be able to live,
那你恐怕得独自享受了
Well, you might have to live it without me,
我会戒掉的 只是现在需要解决些事情
Look, I am gonna stop taking it, There's just some things I have to do
确保我俩的安全 安排好一切 然后我就会戒
to keep us safe and that... To set us up and then I'm gonna get off it,
我本来就是这么打算的      艾迪
I mean, that's the plan,        Eddie...
我真的都打算好了 我发誓
Look, I have a plan, I swear,
我会戒的
I'm gonna get off it,
好吧
OK,
我希望你能做到
I hope you do,
要找我吗
Looking for me?
你以为你能跑掉 是吗
You think you can run out on me, huh?
你以为我不知道你躲在哪里
You think I don't know where you are?
我认为我们之间的生意已经做完了
I was under the impression our business was settled,
再给我些那种药
I want some more of that stuff,
不然我就当场崩了你 自己选
Or I shoot you right here, Take your pick,
这家伙是打发不走的
This guy was not going away.
给他几片药能为我争取到时间
A few pills would buy me some time.
给 我们两清了      走着瞧吧
There it is, We're done,        Oh, yeah, We'll see,
直到我找到更...长久的解决办法
Until I found a more... permanent solution.
除非我真的身陷险境
Unless you see a real threat,
我不希望能察觉到自己身边有保镖
I never want it known that I have any security,
你们不需要为我开道 只需要跟着我
You'll never precede me, you'll always follow me,
永远不要远于15步 两人也不要靠得太近
Never more than 15 steps behind, And never stand too close together,
我希望自己回头的时候还能看见你俩之间有空隙
I want to able to look behind me if the opportunity presents itself,
不要穿同样颜色的西装 这不是什么黑客帝国
And don't wear the same color suit, This isn't The Matrix.
你得明白 艾迪 我把你打发了
You have to know, Eddie, I wrote you off,
我当时病了      你没资格生病
I was sick,        You don't get sick,
生意做到这份上 有口气就得上 你还没死呢
You're playing at this level, you get hit by a car, you don't even die,
你说得完全正确      我知道我是对的
You're absolutely right,        I know I'm right,
我都不知道我在和谁浪费时间
I mean, I didn't know who or what I was talking to,
我当时烧到40度 卡尔 神志恍惚
A hundred and five, That's who you were talking to, Carl, Delirium,
对
Mm-hm,
我把修改过的预测发过来了
I sent over my revised projections,
我没让你发什么预测
I didn't ask for your projections,
我明白 但只要你看过了的话...
I know, but I think if you take a look at them...
我已经看过了 事实上
I already have, As a matter of fact...
我已经根据你的预测炒掉了一些人
...I fired a few people over your projections,
我很抱歉      不 你才没有
I'm sorry,        No, you're not,
你庆幸自己知道我的团队没留意的事
You're relieved that you know things my team missed,
这一刻 一切简直不可思议...
The minute, the instant that's no longer true...
服用NZT两个月后
Two months after I'd started NZT,
我主持了商业史上最大的合并计划
I was brokering the biggest merger in corporate history.
讽刺的是 关键在于原油
Ironically, it's gonna be crude,
原油是我们切入的最佳方位
Crude is gonna be where we're gonna hit them,
这部分利润高达百分之两百
Which yields a prospective profit of 200 percent,
这会让每个人都喜出望外
That makes both of us very happy campers,
我发现只要保持合理摄入量
I found that if I maintained an even dose,
按时吃饭 不沾酒精
remembered to eat, drank no alcohol,
头脑空窗期就再没发生过      你还好吧 艾迪
the blackouts didn't recur.        How you doing, Eddie?
汤姆 衣服里能加暗袋吗
Tom, is it possible to construct an imperceptible compartment?
在这件上面吗
In this jacket?
所有衣服上面      当然可以 先生
In all of them,        Certainly, sir,
与其在这里坐吃山空
Safer though my stash now was,
不如先想办法
I was not sitting around until it ran out.
我能按同样的配方制作出同样的药物吗
Can I combine these ingredients in the same exact quantity,
当然可以 不过
yes, but,
它能否起到同样的作用...不好说
the exact method of delivery to the brain... Darts at a dartboard,
什么意思      还需要临床试验 在人身上试验
Meaning?        Clinical trials, guinea pig people,
花的时间太久了      制药就这么麻烦
That's gonna take too long,        It's what it is,
不然就是在草菅人命 需要12到18个月...
Or you'll kill people, You need 12, to 18 months...
如果你六个月里能做出来我就给你两百万
I'll give you two million dollars if you can do it in six,
我发现我们能降低30%的成本
I found that we can cut costs 30 percent and, um...
失陪一下
Excuse me one second,
我以为之前那事已经解决了 侦探
I thought we straightened this out, Detective,
这和弗农・甘特无关 莫莱先生
This isn't about Vernon Gant, Mr. Morra,
那又是为了什么
What is this about?
玛利亚・温贝里案的目击证人指认这人为嫌疑犯
The witness identified the Maria Winberg suspect as this person,
打算告诉我你四月二日晚上在什么地方吗
Wanna tell me your whereabouts the night of April 2nd?
我没办法再独自隐瞒下去
I couldn't keep this quiet on my own.
于是我请了莫里斯・布兰特 纽约最出色的律师
Enter Morris Brandt... the most lethal lawyer in New York.
很幸运房间已经打扫过了
You're lucky somebody wiped the room,
证据薄弱 最多只能算间接旁证
It's weak, Circumstantial at best,
和我私下透个底 你那天在那里吗
Just between us, were you there?
我记不得了
I don't remember,
我无意对你们让步...
I don't want to make concessions to you...
卡尔・范隆和汉克・阿特伍德
Carl Van Loon and Hank Atwood
都对我即将受到谋杀指控毫不知情
had no idea I might soon be charged with murder.
但SY 艾丹这几家公司
But SyCorps, Andine and others are jockeying
都正在为我们装作没有察觉到的
for the same industrial concessions in Libya
商业利益在利比亚大打出手
that both our companies are pretending we're not sniffing out,
你怎么知道呢
How do you know this?
自上而下收取贿赂的政府本身就腐败不堪 自然
The governmental bribe system is itself corrupt, so, of course,
内线消息 像任何东西一样 都是买得到的
information about its inner workings, like anything, can be bought,
继续
Go on,
如果你看看左下角那排 在2008年
If you take a look at the lower left-hand column, in 2008,
在我们留意到前
five companies were jockeying for a position
已经有五个公司在角力了
before we even took notice,
老天 他看上去不堪一击
Jesus, he looks frail,
可能是装出来的      他还不到60岁
Could be an act,        He's not even 60,
决定好了吗 艾迪 你准备怎么办
So, have you decided, Eddie? What are you gonna do?
并购结束之后? 我不知道
When this is over? I don't know,
你还没告诉我答案
You haven't given me the answer,
你又没有问
You haven't asked the question,
基于我的贡献
Well, given the scale of my contribution,
45吧
let's say 45,
成交 四千五千美元
Done, Forty-five thousand dollars,
四千万是一大笔钱 艾迪
Forty million is plenty, Eddie,
但那之后还会有更多
There's a lot more where that came from,
知道吗 艾迪
You know, Eddie...
也许你考虑的是
...it may be on your mind
不准备继续为我工作
that you're not gonna continue to work for me anymore,
这是一次宝贵的学习经历
This has been the learning experience of my life,
我希望如此 我希望你不会觉得自己已经学得够了
I hope it has, I hope you don't think you've gotten enough from me,
进入下一阶段
On to the next,
要发展职业生涯 我必须不断前行
Well, in order for a career to evolve, I'm gonna have to move on,
你想过没有这只会告诉我
That you would even think that would only show me
你完全没有准备好独自前行
how unprepared you are to be on your own,
我是说 你清楚认识到自己是个怪才
I mean, you do know you're a freak,
你那源于天赐 或者机遇 或者基因
Your deductive powers are a gift from God, or chance,
或者其他任何来源的推理能力
or a stray shot of sperm, or whatever, or whoever the hell wrote
都不是你辛苦挣来的
your life script, a gift not earned,
你不懂我明白的事因为你的能力不是磨练出来的
You do not know what I know because you have not earned those powers,
你对你的能力毫不珍惜
You're careless with those powers,
你挥洒卖弄自己的能力
You flaunt them and you throw them around
就像富二代挥霍他的遗产
like a brat with his trust fund,
你没有经历过一梯梯往上爬的日子
You haven't had to climb up all the greasy little rungs,
你没有被投资人的无聊折磨过
You haven't been bored blind at the fundraisers,
你也没有为了
You haven't done the time
把你第一次婚姻费在做个凤凰男身上
in that first marriage to the girl with the right father,
你觉得自己可以轻松跨越这些阶段
You think you can leap over all in a single bound,
你从不需要为了一个位置使劲浑身解数
You haven't had to bribe or charm or threaten your way
去行贿 色诱 威胁
to a seat at that table,
你不知道要怎么分析你的竞争对手
You don't know how to assess your competition
因为你从未真正竞争过 别指望你有本事和我争
because you haven't competed, Don't make me your competition,
现在 我会给你一笔资金
Now, I'll open up a line of credit for you,
你会想试试身手的
You'll be wanting a few toys,
住酒店已经不再是个办法
Hotel rooms were no longer an option.
我需要的是个堡垒
What I needed was a bunker.
有内置保险箱 中央监控系统
There's a built-in safe, central surveillance,
金库级别的空气压力门
vault grade pneumatic doors.
绝无仅有的三层保全系统
It's an unparalleled three-tier security system,
这是一座风景绝美的堡垒
A fortress with a hell of a view,
开价多少      八百五十万
What's the asking price?        Eight-point-five,
我买了
I'll take it,
毫无疑问他是为NZT而来
Right away, it was obvious he was on NZT.
下周我需要20片药
Next week, I'm gonna need 20 pills,
下周 你可以去见鬼
Next week, you can go fuck yourself!
不是说你会舒坦
Not that you'd feel anything,
我不认为你那些富豪朋友会喜欢
I don't think your Fortune 500 financial friends would appreciate
你和警察之间的那点小小纠纷的
the details of your little dilemma with the police,
周四 药送到这里
Thursday, I'm gonna need the pills here,
变聪明了啊
Getting smarter!
显而易见 不能再这么继续下去
Obviously, this could not go on,
不过这世上
but there is very little on this earth
四千万美金解决不了的事情可不多
that 40 million dollars can't solve.
明早九点钟 阿特伍德就会签字
And tomorrow at nine, Atwood would sign the papers.
这是怎么回事      临阵退缩?
Do you want to call it?        Cold feet?
现在这么说已经太晚了
There was all last night to tell us that,
有消息吗      我马上再联系他 先生
Anything?        I'll call him again, sir.
好吧 他可能会改主意 这也是人之常情
OK, the decision could have changed, That makes sense,
但一声不吭却不合理 交易还会进行
The discourtesy doesn't, It's still on,
基于你的那些表格和预测
Oh, based on your charts and projections,
再和我说一遍 你算哪根葱
You know, remind me, who the fuck are you, anyway?
抱歉 卡尔
I'm sorry, Carl,
我受够这个装腔作势 一文不名的白痴
I've had it with this unqualified, posturing little prick,
闭嘴      什么时候起这成了装神弄鬼
Pull it back,        Since when is this the Delphic Oracle?
别说了      打扰一下 范隆先生
Pull it back,        Excuse me, Mr. Van Loon?
阿特伍德夫人在你办公室等你
Mrs. Atwood is in your office,
阿特伍德夫人 我是卡尔・范隆
Ah, Mrs. Atwood, Carl Van Loon,
我的合伙人 爱德华・莫莱      幸会
My associate, Edward Morra,        Pleasure,
我希望此事尽力保持低调
I wanted to make this as confidential as possible,
当然
Of course,
我丈夫今早突然感到头痛眩晕
My husband experienced some pain and dizziness this morning,
此刻他正在勒诺克斯山医院接受检查
He's currently at Lenox Hill, undergoing tests,
我只是希望表明我们
I just want you to know we have every intention
签署合同的诚意
of signing the contract,
一旦他能够签字 我们立刻办理
And as soon as he is able, we will proceed,
我知道这是老生常谈
I realize this is a useless platitude,
但如果有什么能效劳的地方
but if there's anything that we can do,
请务必不要见外
please don't hesitate to tell us,
我们无疑希望表现出我们的敬意
Obviously, we want to be as helpful and respectful
阿特伍德夫人
as possible, Mrs. Atwood,
谢谢 先生们 我对此深表感激
Thank you, gentlemen, I rely on your discretion,
看样子不会有代理签字了
There won't be a proxy,
不会 像他这种守口如瓶的怎会放权给律师?
No, a cagey prick like him giving away power of attorney?
他最好尽快康复
Well, he'd better get better,
但是阿特伍德不会康复了 因为他没有NZT
But Atwood wouldn't get better. Because Atwood was out of NZT.
为什么要惊讶
Well, why be surprised?
还有多少一夜暴富是NZT的功劳
How many other meteoric rises might be explained by NZT?
至少我是这样
At least I had some.
我的生命没有受到威胁      在这里等
My life wasn't in jeopardy.        You can wait here,
但我的财富 我的自由受到了
Only my money. And my liberty.
我和他们谈过了
I've been all over with them,
所有嫌疑人不允许有任何
We can't allow any disparity in race
人种或明显体格上的差异
or physical type between you and the rest of the line up,
好
OK,
我尽力找了些看着像你的克隆体的家伙
They're as close to your clones as I could possibly get,
目击证人绝对分不清的
It's gotta be just one big handsome blur to this guy.
谁会在那头看
Who was out there?
被害人的丈夫吗
The woman's husband?
酒店员工?
A hotel maid?
我会就此完蛋吗
Was this how it was all going to end?
毫无头绪 他根本认不出
Not the dimmest clue, He was dithering,
"他是从右边数第三个 不 不是他"
"He was the third one from the right, No, Not him,"
给 这西装真棒 手工定制的?
There you go, It's a thing of beauty, You have that made?
没错
I did,
今日市场震荡
...market's been mixed today.
道琼斯指数因范隆集团和汉克・阿特伍德
The Dow has been yo-yoing amidst speculation that
在协商合并的谣传而上下震荡
Van Loon Associates and Hank Atwood have negotiated a merger...
你和谁提起过这个吗
Have you been talking to anyone?
没有 谁也没提 卡尔 我又不傻
No, I haven't been talking to anybody, Carl, I'm not stupid,
我知道你不蠢 艾迪
I know you're not stupid, Eddie,
但不要犯所有聪明人会犯的错
but don't make the classic smart person's mistake,
就是以为没人能比过你
Thinking no one's smarter than you,
你他妈的去哪儿了
Where the hell have you been?
这是你第二次玩失踪了
This is the second time you've turned to vapor,
哪儿也没去 就是去喝个咖啡
I was in the building, I was getting coffee,
怎么了 有新情况吗
Why, has there been movement?
是有新情况 阿特伍德陷入昏迷
Yeah, there's been movement alright, Atwood's in a coma,
他没在耍我们 他确实生命垂危
He wasn't playing us, He's dying,
你对此有什么看法
What do you know about this?
我一时不知要如何作答
I was less than usually equipped to answer.
迟钝感逐渐涌上 该再次服用NZT了
The dullness was coming on. I was overdue to take my NZT.
我的头也开始一阵阵抽痛
And the pain was starting behind my eyes.
失陪一下
Excuse me,
我没让你走
You're not excused,
怎么 你的员工连洗手间也不能去吗 卡尔
What? A man in your employ can't take a piss, Carl?
是布兰特还是谁干的
Was it Brandt or someone else?
在警察局还是什么更衣间丢的?
The police station? A coatroom?
莫莱先生
Mr. Morra,
卡尔 抱歉...      莫莱先生 莫莱先生!
Carl, I'm sorry...        Mr. Morra, Mr. Morra!
你的包裹 刚送到      是的 什么
This just came for you,        Yeah, what?
希望不会 有进展通知我
Hope not, so let me know when you know,
好 现在我准备再问你一次 艾迪
All right, I'm gonna ask you again, Eddie,
你对此有何看法
What do you know about this?
什么 关于泄密吗      不 关于阿特伍德
What? About the leak?        No, About Atwood,
关于阿特伍德的什么
What? What about Atwood?
小子 你在撒谎上还嫩得很呢
Look, you got a long way to go as a liar, kiddo,
卡尔 我不知道你在...      听我说!
Carl, I don't know what you're...        Listen!
我知道你接下来要说的都是废话
What you're about to say is bullshit,
我知道你有事瞒着我
I know there's something you're hiding from me,
我察觉得到 现在
I smell it on you, Right now,
我想知道为什么已经板上钉钉的生意打了水漂!
I wanna know why this clusterfuck of a deal is dead in the water!
卡尔
Carl,
艾迪! 艾迪!
Eddie! Eddie!
今天在勒诺克斯山医院外
Outside Lenox Hill Hospital today,
范隆与阿特伍德的合并出现了更多的变数
more twists and turns in the Van Loon-Atwood merger.
并购仅仅是谣传
There is absolutely no truth to the rumor of this merger.
绝对没有 我丈夫正在接受检查
None whatsoever. My husband is having tests.
这是困难时期
This is a difficult time.
诸位有任何问题可以咨询我们的律师
We would appreciate your directing further questions to our attorney.
目前无可奉告
Yes, we have no further comments at this time.
我们在等待最新检测结果
We're just awaiting the results of the latest round of tests
并期待有奇迹发生
and hoping for the best.
谢谢
Thank you.
艾迪 我知道你在家 艾迪
Eddie, I know you're in there, Eddie,
开门
Open up,
快点
Come on,
快开门
Open the door,
于是我就到了现在这地步
And so, here I am.
我知道那药会一点点将我吞噬
I knew they would kill me slowly and horribly.
但那至少是我的选择
But this choice would at least be mine.
我们都是本能动物 我们想活下去
But we're instinctive creatures. We want to live.
所以我混沌的大脑努力回忆
So my foggy brain tried to remember
还能在哪里再找出一片NZT
where one tablet of NZT might be.
这仅仅是个可能 但有这个可能性也就够了
It was possible. And possible was enough.
你好 艾迪
Hey, Eddie,
你知道我想要更多的药 为什么惹我生气
Now you know I want more, so why would you upset me?
我不喜欢药快用尽的感觉
I don't like being down to this last one,
你不懂得怎么利用它
You don't even know how to use it,
你不会物尽其用
You don't appreciate it,
你瞧 我把它溶解成液体
You see, I dissolve in a solution,
一旦注射 直接进入血液和大脑
You shoot it, It goes straight into the blood and brain,
药效持久得多
Lasts much longer,
那么
So...
你现在准备告诉我剩下的药在哪里了吗
You gonna tell me where the rest is?
我吃光了
I'm plumb out,
给我找
Go look.
要知道 我的人迟早找到它
You know, these guys are gonna find it,
或者我逼你说出来
Or I'm gonna make you tell me,
问题是 哪种办法会先奏效呢
Question is, which is gonna come first?
我想我们会知道答案的 对吗
I guess we're gonna find out, huh?
知道吗 你在浪费我的时间
This is a waste of my time, you know?
我准备从这行洗手不干了
I'm getting out of this side of the business,
去拓展新业务 我开了家进出口公司
I'm branching out, I'm starting import-export company,
非常激动人心
Very exciting stuff,
我忙得很 和你耗是你的荣幸
I got a lot on my plate, You're lucky I'm here,
这里有个保险箱
There's a safe.
要在以前 我会剥了你的皮 割你的肉
Back in the old times, I might peel your skin back, Fillet you,
"割肉" 这词不错
"Fillet," It's a nice word,
我以前不知道这词 哦 那时我的词汇量真贫乏
I didn't know this before, Oh, I had such a poor vocabulary,
但现在我发现了个好东西 谷歌
But then I discovered this thing, Google,
你知道小肠和大肠一共有20英尺长吗
Did you know the small and large intestines is 20 foot long?
我不知道 也不相信
I had no idea, I don't believe it,
我要眼见为实 我很多疑 这又是个新鲜词
I gotta see this for myself, I'm dubious, It's another nice word,
无论如何 我相信你也对此感到好奇
Anyway, I'm sure you're curious, too,
别担心 都消过毒的
Don't worry, everything's sterilized,
结束之前都不会让你断气的
We're gonna keep you alive for the whole shebang,
你可是身处最佳位置哦 艾迪
You're gonna get a front row seat, Eddie,
怎么
What?
算不得什么胜利 不是吗
Not much of a triumph, was it?
因为死的也有可能是我
Because I would die here, too.
只有NZT能救我
Only NZT could help me
而最后的药残存在这个家伙的血液之中
and the last of it was in this fuck's blood stream.
维克多!
Victor!
什么
What?
喂!
Hey!
我看不见
I can't see.
在你右边 开枪
On your right, shoot him.
维克多?
Victor?
警察事后会得知
The police would later note
我公寓的前任主人是个军火商
that my apartment's previous owner was an arms dealer.
自然 这些闯入者也是对他不满的客户
Of course, these intruders had been his dissatisfied clients.
夜还长得很
And the night was still young.
我相信你肯定对你老板身上发生的事感到好奇
I'm sure you're curious about what happened to your boss,
至少我很好奇
I know I certainly am,
我是说 如果我的律师真在为阿特伍德先生效力
I mean, if my attorney was really working for Mr. Atwood,
想要竭力拯救他的话 他怎么会死
trying to save his life, why is he dead?
怎么没见到这位忠心耿耿的下属
I mean, at what point was the pony express supposed to ride in
带着救命灵药飞奔而来呢
with his life-saving medication?
他的老板死了
His boss was dead.
因此我再也无关紧要
So, I didn't matter now.
但他不满莫里斯・布兰特
But he did not appreciate that Morris Brandt
独吞了药物
had kept the pills for himself.
一切仍有挽回的余地
And it was all still possible.
十二个月以后
TWELVE MONTHS LATER
实际上 票已售罄
Actually, no, there's no more tickets,
我明白 临时多出来的募捐人 这倒头一次
Yeah, I know, An overbooked fundraiser, That's a first,
他刚好过来了 我问问他
Well, here he comes, I'll ask him,
这样看上去好多了
Oh, that's much better,
非常好      谢谢 先生
Great job,        Thank you, sir,
你好 莫莱先生
Hi, Mr. Morra,
爱德华!
Edward!
我想我们这是要有第二次人满为患的募捐晚会了
I think we're looking at a second overflow event,
大量捐款不断涌入 我觉得
There's a wave of donations coming in and I don't think
那些人都没怎么犹豫就决定了
they're even gonna try a second debate,
太好了      坚持住
Great.        Hold on,
EC公司的人在你办公室等你
A guy from Eiben-Chemcorp's in your office,
我约了人吃午餐      他们是你最大的捐助人
I have a lunch,        They're your biggest contributor,
好歹随便应付下
Give him his two crappy little minutes,
EC制药?      对
Eiben-Chemcorp Pharmaceuticals?        Yeah,
终于见到了维持这一切运转的功臣
Finally get to meet the guys that keep the lights on,
卡尔!      莫莱先生
Carl!        Mr. Morra,
真是意外 他们告诉我来的是EC公司的人
What a surprise, They told me somebody from Eiben was coming,
EC公司 没错 那现在是我的公司
Chemcorp, Yeah, that's me now,
我在渐渐退出能源市场
I'm moving out of the energy business,
拜托 这就像海夫纳离开"花花公子"杂志一样
Come on, That's like Hef moving out of the mansion,
几个月前我买下了EC公司
Yeah, I bought Eiben a couple of months ago,
你竟然没听说这事
I'm surprised you didn't hear,
没有 没有 他们让我忙得团团转
No, No, Well, they really keep me hopping here,
这一切都是有回报的 莫莱议员
Well, it's gonna pay off, Senator Morra,
参议院 谁知道呢...
The Senate, Who knows...
以后又会有何发展 艾迪
Everything's a technicality from here on in, isn't it, Eddie?
我们都知道未来的方向 只要你能维持现状
I think we both know where it's headed, if you can maintain,
你想过药用完了之后要怎么办吗
Have you asked yourself what you're gonna do when you run out?
你啥时候知道的      有关系吗 反正我知道了
When did you know?        Does it matter? I know now,
我真希望你来找的是我 艾迪
I wish you'd come to me at first, Eddie,
我本可以用33块一股的价格收购EC的
I could have bought Eiben at 33 a share,
我们本可以成为合作伙伴
We could have been partners,
NZT是EC制造的
So, Eiben makes NZT,
官方记录上没有这条
Well, it'll never officially exist,
显然我不需要再指出这对你有什么好处
Obviously, I don't need to point out the advantages for you,
我想你也许需要
Oh, I think maybe you do,
给你无限供应 我们都知道你别处弄不到了
Limitless supply, We know you can't get any more,
你确定?
You sure about that?
他们今早刚刚关闭了你的实验室
They shut down your lab this morning,
艾迪 我只是想帮你 仅此而已
Eddie, I just want to help you, that's all,
为你提供源源不断的药物
Keep you supplied, No disruption in service,
让你能安心做事 仅此而已
Give you peace of mind, That's all,
作为回报 我需要做什么
And in return, I do what?
听从点建议 也许吧 一开始我不会成天来打扰你
Get a little advice, maybe, I won't be bothering you much at first,
但之后呢 你会拿什么样的事来找我
And later, What are you gonna be bothering me with?
既然谈到你奋斗的方向
Well, given where you're heading,
某些主意可能会有点激进
some of our ideas are a bit ambitious,
但是 我认为都是可以实现的
But hey, I think they're achievable,
如果我不喜欢你的主意怎么办
And what if I don't like your ideas?
那我们就会说 "祝你成功"
Then we'll say, "Godspeed,"
然后你的生命之烛也许就要风雨飘摇了
And your candle will have shed a brief, but lovely light,
但听我说 艾迪 我们
But you know what, Eddie, let's not even
现在还是不谈这么远
go there right now,
现在 我希望让你保持智慧
Right now, I just want to keep you brilliant...
...健康 来吧 我们一起去吃个饭
...and healthy, Come on, Let's go get some lunch,
你先请 议员
After you, Senator,
谢谢你来拜访 卡尔
Thanks for stopping by, Carl,
给我们一点时间
Give us a second,
你这是在干嘛 你想成为美国总统
What are you doing? Do you want to be President of the United States
还是想变成植物人?      我倒愿意碰碰运气
or brain dead, stuck full of tubes?        I'll take my chances,
我说过你没机会的 我们关闭了你的实验室
I told you your chances don't exist, We shut down your lab,
你难道没想过狡兔三窟
You don't think some smartass on NZT
我可能有不止一个实验室?
might have two or three or even four labs?
那又怎样 你再也生产不出来了
So what? You're not making any more,
没错 我没再生产了
That's right, I'm not,
我有更好的办法 一旦你知道了它的成分
I thought better of it, See, once you know what's in it,
你可以调整 重制它 消除缺陷 减少用量
you can tweak it, re-engineer it, Get the bugs out, Taper off,
我完全戒了 卡尔
I'm off it, Carl,
戒或者没戒
Well, on it or off it,
都不意味着你不能为我工作
there's no scenario where you're not working for me,
你怎么报偿我 用香烟吗
How you gonna pay me? In cigarettes?
去年一年
Last year you traded
你就交易了17次内幕情报      你在威胁我吗
inside information 17 times,        You threatening me?
在迪拜开空头支票 往智利扔工业垃圾
Blank checks from Dubai, Dumping in Chile,
导致官员失踪
Disappeared officials,
我说 你简直是站在风口浪尖了...
I mean, you shed a spot light...
你想和我开战吗
Do you want to go to war with me?
你给我听清楚 我不打算扯远
And trust me when I say this, I'm not even being creative,
但你没有任何可能在做出这么多指控之后
There's no way you can be making accusations like that
还能全身而退
and be walking around alive,
这就表明了你找我对阵时
That you would even think that shows me
准备有多么不充分
how unprepared you are to fight me,
你已经没有和我对着干的资本了
You're no longer equipped to fight me,
我也许已经脱瘾了 但你觉得我什么也没学到吗
I may be off it, but you think I didn't learn anything?
我的神经元没有进化?
That my synapses didn't change?
我什么也没学到?
That I kept absolutely nothing?
你不晓得我会是个多么可怕的敌人
You have no idea what kind of enemy I can be,
那辆货车会追那辆出租车的尾      什么
That van's gonna rear-end that taxi,        What?
那司机在走神 他在发短信 时速是30英里/小时
The driver's distracted, He's texting, He's going 30 miles an hour,
需要提前60英尺刹车 没有足够减速空间
He has 60 feet to stop, He doesn't have room,
什么货车
What van?
我无所不知 卡尔
I see everything, Carl,
我比任何人都看得更长远
I'm 50 moves ahead of you and everybody else,
你凭什么认为我不会让人此刻正用枪指着你
What makes you think I don't have a guy with a bead on you right now?
你怎么知道你明年这会儿还活着
How do you know you're gonna be alive this time next year?
你在干什么 放手 你在干什么
What are you doing? You get your hands off me, What are you doing?
心跳有杂音
Something's pumping half-mass in there,
心脏壁肿大
The walls of your heart are dilated,
主动脉瓣狭小 需要进行换心手术
Your aortic valve's steno, So you're gonna need to get that replaced,
但你已经知道了
But you already knew that,
你该为此感到庆幸
You know, you should really be glad about this,
让我为你工作? 你迟早被我玩弄于股掌之间
'Cause me working for you? You'd end up as my bitch,
也许我们都该冷静下 然后再谈
Maybe we should cool off, Talk again,
我可不这么认为
I don't think so,
别忘了投票
Don't forget to vote,
爱德华
Edward,
你没事吧
You good?
没事 告诉过你我约了人吃饭
Yeah, Told you I have a lunch,
抱歉我迟到了      没关系
Sorry I'm late,        Hey, Don't worry,
今天过得如何      好多了
How's your day going?        Ah, I've had better,
我还是不习惯你的新发型
I still can't deal with that haircut,
走在街上都认不出来了
I wouldn't even recognize you on the street,
我改头换面了
Well, I'm a new man,
我已经点过菜了
I've already ordered,
(这段疑似中文的对话请大家自行想象)
怎么
What?
破烂熊字幕组
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
欢迎加入